nysaves.org 2006-04-29

# Privacy Notices

        Privacy Notices
                 New York State Personal Privacy                                Information We May Obtain
                 Protection Law Notice                                          As part of providing you products or services, we may obtain
                 Personal information is being requested from you by the Office personal information from the following sources:
                 of the New York State Comptroller (OSC) and the New York       • Information you provide to us on applications and other
                 State Higher Education Services Corporation (HESC) (the           forms, that you otherwise enter on our website, or that you
                 Program Administrators of New York’s 529 College Savings          provide to us in writing or by telephone, such as when you
                 Program) and by Upromise Investments, Inc. (the Program           contact our customer service staff. This information may
                 Manager), and The Vanguard Group, Inc. or Columbia                include items such as your name, address, telephone
                 Management Group, Inc. (the Investment Advisors), or their        number and social security number. In addition, please see
                 employees, agents, or representatives.                            “Use of Cookies” below for information we receive
                 Personal information you submit will be maintained in the         automatically when you visit our website.
                 records of New York’s 529 College Savings Program. The         • Information from your transactions with us, our affiliates or
                 officials responsible for the Program records are the Program     nonaffiliated third parties such as account activity and your
                 co-directors employed by OSC and HESC. Their address is P.O.      purchase information in our Rewards Service.
                 Box 1086, New York, NY 10021-0036. The telephone number        • Information from third parties, including public sources,
                 of the Program is 1-877-NY-SAVES.                                 such as verification services and consumer reporting
                 Personal information is collected from you under the authority    agencies (to comply with regulatory requirements, ensure
                 of the New York State College Choice Tuition Savings Program      the accuracy of data and prevent fraud, for example), or
                 Act (Article 14-A of the New York Education Law) and section      from other sources (such as from other institutions like a
                 529 of the Internal Revenue Code. The personal information        bank or broker you use to transfer funds into a Upromise
                 you submit will be used to maintain records of your               account, or public sources).
                 contributions to the Program and the earnings on those         We use the information we obtain in order to develop, offer
                 contributions and to process transactions you request. If you  and deliver our products and services, to process transactions
                 decline to submit the requested information it may be          in your accounts, and to fulfill legal and regulatory
                 impossible for you to be enrolled in the Program or for the    requirements. We limit the collection and use of customer
                 Program to process transactions you request.                   information to the minimum we require to deliver superior
                                                                                service to our customers (including advising our customers
                 Upromise Privacy Policy                                        about our products, services and other opportunities) and to
                 The following information has been provided by Upromise,       administer our business.
                 Inc. for inclusion herein. Such information has not been
                 independently verified by the Comptroller, HESC or Vanguard    Sharing Information With Our Affiliates
                 and no representation is made by the Comptroller, HESC or      By sharing your personal information with our affiliates, we
                 Vanguard as to its accuracy or completeness. Protecting your   can better understand and meet your college savings needs
                 privacy is a top priority at Upromise. We want you to          by letting you know about products, services and promotional
                 understand how we handle the personal information about        offers in which you are most likely to be interested. For
                 you that we may obtain, and how we may and may not share       example, if you have a Rewards Service account that has
                 it. This statement covers all of our information handling      accumulated sufficient funds, you may be interested in
                 practices for Upromise, Inc. and its affiliates (companies     opening an account with New York’s 529 College Savings
                 under common ownership with Upromise) for the benefit of       Program Direct Plan, and we can contact you directly about
                 current and past customers. Please also see our separate       how to do that.
                 statement, Privacy of Upromise Rewards Service at
                 www.upromise.com, for additional information about our         Unless you tell us not to, we may share with our affiliates all of
                 practices relating to our Rewards Service. Please see our      the information we obtain about you. If you prefer that we not
                 supplemental statement, Policy Regarding the Program,          share with our affiliates consumer report information about you
                 below for additional information about Upromise’s practices    that we may receive from third parties, you may direct us not to
                 relating specifically to the use of personal information       do so by sending us an email at customercare@upromise.com
                 provided to Upromise Investments, Inc. in connection with      containing your name, address and account number, or by
                 your New York 529 College Savings Program account.             calling the following toll free number: 1-800-877-6647. Please
                                                                                be aware that we may continue to share any other information
                                                                                as permitted by law.
NY529 PAGE 1

Sharing Information With Nonaffiliated                              Choices Regarding the Receipt of
Third Parties                                                       Marketing Messages
Information about our customers is an important part of our         You may choose whether and to what extent you receive
business. We do not share your personal information with third      marketing messages from Upromise about products and
parties except as permitted or required by law, including as        services offered by Upromise or third parties. If you do not
provided below:                                                     wish to receive marketing messages, you may opt out at any
• Agents and Service Providers. In order to provide our             time. And we offer you choices, so that you receive offers that
    products and services, we may share any of the information      are of interest to you in the ways you wish. If you do not wish
    we gather about you with agents and service providers to        to receive messages, you may opt out by updating your
    perform functions on our behalf, such as to send e-mail and     account profile at any time on the Upromise website, or by
    postal mail, analyze data, provide marketing services,          contacting a customer service representative at 1-800-877-
    process applications and credit card payments, and service      6647. We reserve the right to send you specific administrative
    accounts. These service providers have access to personal       notices that are required by law, regulation, or as needed to
    information needed to perform their functions, but may not      service your account.
    use it for other purposes.
                                                                    Security of Your Personal Information
• Protection of Upromise and Others. We may disclose
    personal information about you to third parties when we         Upromise is committed to earning and keeping your trust. We
    believe such disclosure is appropriate to comply with a         understand the need for our customers’ personal information
    legal requirement, such as a law, regulation, court order,      to remain secure and private, and we have deployed industry-
    subpoena or search warrant, or in the course of a legal         recognized safeguards that meet federal standards for the
    proceeding. We may also disclose personal information as        protection of your personal information, including: monitoring
    we believe appropriate to enforce or apply our rights under     for intrusion attempts; SSL (Secure Socket Layer), data, and
    our agreements with customers, to protect the rights,           password encryption technology; firewalls and systems
    property or safety of Upromise, our customers and others,       monitoring; and security audits and inspections. Only
    including exchanging information for fraud protection and       authorized employees have access to customer information.
    credit risk reduction.                                          Please remember that you also play a valuable part in data
• Business Transfers. If there is a change of control in            security. You should never share your Upromise password with
    Upromise’s business (whether by merger, sale, or                anyone. If you feel your password has been compromised, you
    otherwise), its customer information could be sold as part      should change it immediately. After you have finished using
    of that transaction and your personally identifying             our site, you should log out of your Upromise account and exit
    information potentially could be used by the purchaser.         your browser so that no unauthorized persons can use our site
    However, if that business materially changes this statement     under your name and account information.
    or the information-handling practices as described in this
    statement, you will have a choice as to whether your            Collection of Information from Children
    existing information is used in a new manner.                   None of Upromise’s products or services are intended for
If we ever make the decision to share customer personal             purchase by children. Accordingly, Upromise does not
information with third parties so that they may market their        knowingly collect, either online or offline, personally
products and services directly to you, we will notify you           identifiable information from children under the age of 13.
ahead of time, and we will not share your information
without your consent.                                               Changes to This Privacy Statement
                                                                    If we materially change this statement or our information-
Use of Cookies                                                      handling practices as described in this statement, we will notify
Our web servers place and read “cookies” on our site’s visitors’    you at least 30 days prior to their implementation. You will have
computers for a variety of purposes. Cookies are small data         choices as to whether we use your existing information in a
files that are stored on an Internet user’s computer by a web       new manner.
server. One important use of cookies is to help identify you
while you are logged in to the Upromise site. Consequently, if      Policy Regarding the Program
your browser does not accept session cookies, you will be           Upromise Investments maintains Program records as required
unable to enroll or log in to our service using our site. You will, by Article 14-A of the New York State Education Law, which
however, be able to browse our site as a visitor. The               governs the Program’s operations, and applicable New York
information Upromise collects from cookies and web server           law. As a result, Upromise Investments does not, for example,
logs is used to administer the web service and customize            share personal information you provide in connection with your
information you receive when visiting our site. Upromise may        New York’s 529 College Savings Program account with its
also use and share aggregate information from cookies and           affiliates, or use it to develop, offer and deliver products and
web server logs to analyze and improve our web service              services, or send marketing messages to you without your
offerings. This information does not identify individual visitors   consent. However, information you provide to Upromise in
or customers.                                                       connection with your Upromise Rewards account may be
                                                                                                                                  NY529 PAGE 2

             shared among Upromise affiliates, used to develop, offer and    Personal information collected from any source may include
             deliver products and services, or send marketing messages to    your:
             you without your consent as described above in the general      • Name and address.
             Upromise Privacy Policy for Upromise and its affiliates.
                                                                             • Social Security or taxpayer identification number.
             If you have questions about Upromise’s Privacy Policy or        • Assets.
             Upromise Investment’s policy regarding the Program, please
                                                                             • Income.
             contact us at customercare@upromise.com, or call 1-800-877-
             6647, or write to us at: Attention: Chief Privacy Officer,      • Account balance.
             Upromise, Inc. 117 Kendrick Street, Suite 200, Needham,         • Investment activity.
             Massachusetts 02494.                                            • Accounts at other institutions.
             Vanguard Privacy Policy                                         How We Handle Your Personal Information
             Provided by the Vanguard funds,                                 We do not sell information about current or former clients or
             The Vanguard Group, Inc.,                                       their accounts to third parties. Nor do we share such
             Vanguard Marketing Corporation,                                 information, except when needed to complete transactions at
             Vanguard Advisers, Inc.,                                        your request or to make you aware of related financial
             Vanguard Fiduciary Trust Company, and                           products and services that we offer. Here are the details:
             Vanguard National Trust Company.                                • In order to complete certain transactions or account
                                                                                changes that you direct, it may be necessary to provide
             Our Commitment to You                                              identifying information to companies, individuals, or groups
             As a Vanguard investor, you have entrusted to our care not         that are not affiliated with Vanguard. For example, if you
             only your hard-earned money but your personal and financial        ask to transfer assets from another financial institution to
             data as well. We recognize that your relationship with us is       Vanguard, we will need to provide certain information about
             based on trust, and that you expect us to act responsibly and      you to that company to complete the transaction.
             in your best interests. Because your personal and financial     • In order to alert you to other Vanguard financial products
             data are your private information, we hold ourselves to the        and services, we may share your information within the
             highest standards in their safekeeping and use.                    Vanguard family of affiliated companies. This would
             This means, most importantly, that we do not sell client           include, for example, sharing your information within
             information—whether it is your personal information or             Vanguard to make you aware of new Vanguard funds, or the
             the fact that you are a Vanguard client—to anyone.                 brokerage services offered through Vanguard’s brokerage
                                                                                companies, or the asset management and trust services
             Instead, your information is used by us primarily to complete
                                                                                offered through Vanguard’s trust companies and registered
             transactions that you request or to make you aware of other
                                                                                investment advisors.
             financial products and services that we offer.
                                                                             • In certain instances, we may contract with nonaffiliated
             The Information We Collect About You                               companies to perform services for us. Where necessary, we
                                                                                will disclose information we have about you to these third
             You provide personal information when you complete a
                                                                                parties. In all such cases, we provide the third party with
             Vanguard account application. (If you enter information in an
                                                                                only the information necessary to carry out its assigned
             online application, we may store the information even if you
                                                                                responsibilities and only for that purpose. And we require
             don’t complete or submit the application.) You also provide
                                                                                these third parties to treat your private information with the
             personal information when you request a transaction that
                                                                                same high degree of confidentiality that we do.
             involves Vanguard or one of the Vanguard-affiliated companies.
                                                                             • Finally, we will release information about you if you direct
             In addition to personal information you provide to us, we may      us to do so, if we are compelled by law to do so, or in other
             receive information about you that you authorize third parties     legally limited circumstances (for example, to protect your
             to provide to us. We also may obtain personal information          account from fraud).
             from third parties in order to verify your identity and prevent
             fraud, or to help us identify products and services that may    How We Protect Privacy Online
             benefit you.
                                                                             Our concern for the privacy of our shareholders naturally
                                                                             extends to those who use our website, Vanguard.com®. Our
                                                                             website uses some of the most secure forms of online
                                                                             communication available, including data encryption, Secure
                                                                             Sockets Layer (“SSL”) protocol, and user names and
                                                                             passwords. These technologies provide a high level of security
                                                                             and privacy when you access your account information, initiate
                                                                             online transactions, or send secure messages.
NY529 PAGE 3

Vanguard.com offers customized features that require our use          What You Can Do
of “HTTP cookies”—tiny pieces of information that we ask
                                                                      For your protection, we recommend that you do not provide
your browser to store. However, we make very limited use of
                                                                      your account information, user name, or password to anyone.
these cookies. We don’t use them to pull data from your hard
                                                                      If you become aware of any suspicious activity relating to your
drive, to learn your e-mail address, or to view data in cookies
                                                                      account, please contact us immediately.
created by other websites. We will not share the information
in our cookies or give others access to it—except to help us          We’ll Keep You Informed
better serve your investment needs.
                                                                      As required by federal law, we will notify you of our privacy
You can visit our website to read more details about its              policy annually. We reserve the right to modify this policy at
security and privacy features.                                        any time, but rest assured that if we do change it, we will tell
                                                                      you promptly.
How We Safeguard Your Personal Information
                                                                      Special Note to New York’s 529 College Savings Program
We restrict access to information about you to those
                                                                      Account Owners: Unless you consent, you will not receive
Vanguard employees who need to know the information to
                                                                      solicitations from Vanguard about non-Program products and
provide products or services to you. We maintain strict
                                                                      services by participating in New York’s 529 College Savings
physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect
                                                                      Program Direct Plan.
your personal information.
New York’s 529 College Savings Program Direct Plan is described in the current applicable Program Brochure and Tuition Savings
Agreement. Accounts are opened by completing an Enrollment Application. All of these should be read carefully before opening an
account. None of the State of New York, its agencies, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC), The Vanguard Group, nor
Upromise insures accounts or guarantees the principal deposited therein or any investment returns on any account or investment
portfolio. The value of your account will vary based on market conditions and the performance of the investment options you select,
and may be more or less than the amount you deposit. Investments may be made through Upromise Investments, Inc., and Vanguard
Marketing Corporation as distributors.
                                                                                                                                  NY529 PAGE 4
                                                                                                                                 NY529PR 112003
